<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "dtd/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY logtracker "<emphasis>Instant Log Tracker</emphasis>">	]>
<chapter id="globalConfig">
	<title>Configuration</title>
	<xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="LogParserConfig.xml" />
	<sect1>
		<title id="confLogSources">Configure Log-Sources</title>
		<figure id="logFileSelDialog"><title>The Log File Selection Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject condition="fo"><imagedata fileref="LogFileSources.svg" format="SVG" scalefit="1" width="100%"/></imageobject>
				<imageobject condition="html"><imagedata fileref="LogFileSources.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>Log files that are to monitored are specified using the <emphasis>Log File Selection Dialog</emphasis>(see <xref linkend="logFileSelDialog"/>)</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry><term>Add new File Selection Dialog</term>
				<listitem><para>Press this button to create a new Log File Selection Dialog panel.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Close File Selection Dialog</term>
				<listitem><para>Close the Log File Selection Dialog panel with this button. All dependent panels will be closed, as well and
					the processing of the files is stopped.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Add new Log File Line</term>
				<listitem><para>Open an "open File" dialog box and let the user choose one ore more log files. The selected log files will be
					added to the log file table.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Edit Log File</term>
				<listitem><para>Click onto a Log file path in order to modify the log file.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Edit Log File Name</term>
				<listitem><para>Double Click to edit the Log File Name. The Log File Name is used through the application for specifying the
					source of a data item. A part of the log file path is used as default name.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Remove Log File</term>
				<listitem><para>Remove a single log file from the list.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Log File Format</term>
				<listitem><para>Specify the log parser configuration that should be used for interpreting the log files. Log parser configurations
					are specified in the Log Parser Configuration Dialog. See <xref linkend="confLogParsers"/>. 
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Limit Data</term>
				<listitem><para>Filter the data that is processed by &logtracker;. Only consider lines with an occurrence time that is more recent
					than the configured amount of time. This feature is useful when processing very large files, while only events that happened
					recently are considered.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Start Processing</term>
				<listitem><para>Apply the log file configuration, start reading the files and start processing. If data processing already active,
					it is stopped and restarted based on the new configuration.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Activity Status</term>
				<listitem><para>Shows processing of the files is active, inactive, or sleeping.</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</sect1>
	<sect1><title>Global Configuration Parameters</title>
		<para>Global configuration parameters are configured by opening the global configuration panel. Press the <emphasis>Open Configuration
			 Dialog Box</emphasis> button for this purpose (<xref linkend="userInterface"/>).</para>
		<figure id="globalConfigPanel"><title>Global Configuration Parameters</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject condition="fo"><imagedata fileref="GlobalConfig.png" format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="50%"/></imageobject>
				<imageobject condition="html"><imagedata fileref="GlobalConfig.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>The configuration parameters and their meaning are:</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry><term>Window Title</term>
				<listitem><para>Set the title of the main &logtracker; application window. This is especially useful, when multiple &logtracker;
					instances are running.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Time Stamp Format String</term>
				<listitem><para>Set the display format of time stamps throughout the application. The Java 
					<ulink url="https://docs.oracle.com/javase/8/docs/api/java/text/SimpleDateFormat.html">SimpleDateFormat</ulink>
					notation is used.
				</para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry><term>Initial Time Range Max</term>
				<listitem><para>Is used as the maximum value for the time range for new scatter plots (see <xref linkend="call_stats"/>). </para></listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title id="confFiles">Configuration Files</title>
		<para>&logtracker; configurations can be stored in configuration files. It supports two basic forms:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para><emphasis>Complete configuration files</emphasis> contain information about all configurable parameters of a running
				&logtracker; instance.<footnote><para>In the present version, the layout of the &logtracker;'s main window and its panels is 
				not part of the configuration.</para></footnote>
			</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para><emphasis>Log Parser configuration files</emphasis> contain only log parser configuration data.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Both types store their information in XML format<footnote><para>&logtracker; versions prior to 2.0 have used a binary format for the
			configuration files. The actual version is still able to read and understand those binary files, but it can only store configuration
			in the new XML-based format. Migration old config-files is easy: just open and store them with &logtracker;.
		    </para></footnote> as an "*.ltc"-file (ltc = LogTracker Configuration). A <emphasis>complete</emphasis>
			configuration file is created, when a user presses the <emphasis>Save LogTracker Configuration</emphasis> button at the top of the main 
			application window (see <xref linkend="userInterface"/>). A <emphasis>Log Parser configuration file is created</emphasis> when a user 
			presses the <emphasis>Save to file</emphasis>-button in the <emphasis>parser configuration dialog box</emphasis> (see <xref linkend="parserConfig"/>).
			Only the configurations of the parsers that are selected in the parser configuration table are stored into the file. Multiple parsers can be
			selected by Shift-Clicking multiple lines.
		</para>
		<para>The according <emphasis>Load Configuration Files</emphasis> and <emphasis>Load from File</emphasis> buttons have a corresponding effect.
			The first, loads a full configuration. The second loads only parser configurations. When loading, the existing application configuration
			is not overwritten. The new configuration is rather added as additional information: New log parser configurations are added to the existing
			ones. Additional log sources are added to new instances of <emphasis>Log file selection dialogs</emphasis>.
		</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
