<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "dtd/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY logtracker "<emphasis>Instant Log Tracker</emphasis>">	]>
<sect1>
	<title>Log Tracker Data flow</title>
	<para>&logtracker; reads and constantly monitors log files. The data that is found in the files constantly flows through the application
		and is collected, processed, and evaluated in multiple steps.
	</para>
	<figure id="dataFlow"><title>The data flow in &logtracker;</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject condition="fo"><imagedata fileref="DataFlow.svg" format="SVG" width="15cm"/></imageobject>
			<imageobject condition="html"><imagedata fileref="DataFlow.png" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The principal stages are:</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry><term>Read</term>
			<listitem><para>Log files are opened and read on a per line basis.
				&logtracker; automatically continues to monitor all configured log files: Whenever new data is appended, that new data is read
				and sent through the processing pipeline. As a consequence, many tables and graphs are updated automatically as soon as new
				data becomes available.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry><term>Interpret</term>
			<listitem><para>The content of the log lines is interpreted according to the log parser configuration. Interesting text blocks, such
			as timestamps, users, severity levels, service names, response times, correlation ids, etc. are extracted, converted and stored in
			&logtracker;s memory.</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry><term>Combine</term>
			<listitem><para>If more than one file is monitored within one data line, the data from the two sources are combined and ordered
				by the occurrence time. The <emphasis>combine</emphasis>-Element may produce some delay, because it tries to make sure
				that data is delivered in the right order.  
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry><term>Evaluate and visualize</term>
			<listitem><para>The data is evaluated and visualized in the next stage, eventually by showing up some additional panels. The
			kind of panels depends on the flavor of the log files that are analyzed in this data line. More information can be found in
				<xref linkend="call_stats"/>, <xref linkend="error_logs"/>, and <xref linkend="corr_data"/>.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
	<para>&logtracker; configuration is organized along <emphasis>data pipelines</emphasis>. One data pipeline can collect data from exactly one 
		type of log files. The log file type is associated with a log file type.
	</para>
</sect1>
