<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "dtd/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY logtracker "<emphasis>Instant Log Tracker</emphasis>">
	]>
<sect1 id="error_logs"><title>Working with Message or Error-Logs</title>
	<para>Message log files contain information about events that occur within a system. Their main scope is not performance, but rather
		health state of the system and possible problems.
		Message log records typically have a severity level such as ERROR, WARNING, or INFO.
		Message Log File evaluation can be initiated by
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem><para>choosing appropriate log files in the <emphasis>Log File Selection Dialog</emphasis>
		(see <xref linkend="confLogSources"/>)</para>. Such log files typically contain one or more log lines
		per message.
		</listitem>
		<listitem><para>choosing a log parser configuration with a <emphasis>Error Log File</emphasis>
			Parser Type.
		</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>pressing the <emphasis>Apply</emphasis> button</para></listitem>.
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>&logtracker;'s can recognize "similar" messages and groups them automatically.</para>
	<figure id="messagePanel"><title>A sample Message-Log panel</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject condition="fo"><imagedata fileref="MessageLogPanel.png" format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
			<imageobject condition="html"><imagedata fileref="MessageLogPanel.png" format="PNG"/>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para><xref linkend="messagePanel"/> shows a sample of a message panel: Grouped messages are arranged in a table, one group per row.
		The table is sorted by the descending message severity.
		The columns show:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem><para>The severity of the messages of the group.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The date and time of the occurrence of the last message of the group.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The number of messages in this group.</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>The message content of the last message of the group.</para></listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>Message groups that contain messages that occurred within the last ten minutes are colored: Recent errors have a red, recent
		warnings, a yellow and other recent messages have a green background.
	</para>
	<para>The column with of the table can be adjusted with the mouse. Click and drag the right border of a column header cell for that purpose.
		Table columns can be sorted by left-clicking the column header cell.
	</para>
	<para>When the user clicks within the row of the table, a <emphasis>log message detail window</emphasis> will pop up and show the individual members of
		a message group, i.e. all similar messages. A sample message detail window is shown in <xref linkend="messageDetail"/>.
	</para>
	<figure id="messageDetail"><title>A sample Message Detail Window</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject condition="fo"><imagedata fileref="MessageDetailWindow.png" format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="100%"/>
			<imageobject condition="html"><imagedata fileref="MessageDetailWindow.png" format="PNG"/>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The <emphasis>message detail window</emphasis> consists of three parts:</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry><term>The message distribution plot</term>
			<listitem><para>shows the temporal distribution of the member messages of this group. Messages are automatically
				clustered based on their occurrence time and based on the scale of the plot. The position on the horizontal axis
				of the bars indicates the occurrence time, the height of the bars indicate the number of messages within a specific
				group. The zoom in can be done by selecting a rectangle with the mouse. A zoom out can be achieved by the use
				of the context menu, that can be brought up by right clicking in the plot.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry><term>The message table</term>
			<listitem><para>shows the individual messages with their occurrence time, the calling user, the log source and the message
				content.
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry><term>The message pane</term>
			<listitem><para>Select a single message within the <emphasis>message table</emphasis> and its full details are displayed
				in the message pane. The message pane is especially useful, when a message spans over multiple lines.<footnote><para>&logtracker;
					only keeps pointers to the messages in its memory. The full message content is only read from the log file when a user selects
					it. This behavior can lead to unexpected results, when a server uses log file rotation, since the message pointer in memory
					may point to a location that doesn't exist anymore or contains content that has no relation to the log line. Future
					versions of &logtracker; may include support for log-file rotation.
				</para></footnote>
			</para></listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</sect1>
