<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "dtd/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY logtracker "<emphasis>Instant Log Tracker</emphasis>">
	]>
<chapter>
	<title>Install and Run</title>
	<sect1><title>Prerequisites</title>
	<para>&logtracker; requires a Java Run Time Environment of at least version 1.8. If your system does not yet have it, you can download
		it from the <ulink url="http://www.java.com/de/download/" type="_blank">http://www.java.com/de/download/</ulink> Site.
	</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
	<title>Install and Run</title>
	<para>&logtracker; basically consists of one single executable jar-file "<code>logtracker.jar</code>". Normally it's sufficient
		copy it onto a computer that has physical access to the log files that need to be investigated. On most platforms <code>logtracker.jar</code> can
		be launched by the normal procedure as you would use for any program.
	</para>
	<para>If double-clicking that file does not work for some reason, you can launch it "manually" with:</para>
	<programlisting>java -jar logtracker.jar [&lt;logtracker-config-file&gt;]</programlisting>
	<para>The parameter <code>log-tracker-config-file</code> is optional. As an alternative you could pass list of log files as parameters.</para>
	<para>There are special versions of the program for <emphasis>Windows</emphasis> and <emphasis>Mac OS</emphasis>:</para>
	<para>For <emphasis>Windows</emphasis>, there is a file called <code>logtracker.exe</code>. The main advantage of this file over the executable jar
		is the fact, that it comes with a nice icon and that it can be associated with file extensions, such as <code>.ltc</code> (Log-Tracker Configuration 
		Files) or <code>.log</code>. <code>logtracker.exe</code> only works, if a Java 8 Runtime Environment is installed on your machine.
	</para>
	<para>For <emphasis>Mac OS</emphasis>, there is a <code>logtracker.zip</code>-file, which contains a LogTracker application bundle. Unzip the file
		to the the directory, where you want to place the application bundle and launch it by double clicking it. The application bundle automatically
		assigns itself to the <code>.ltc</code> file extension.
	</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1><title>Memory considerations</title>
		<para>&logtracker; keeps important parts of the investigated log files in its memory. Depending on the size of the file
			the memory that is needed can raise substantially. If there is not enough heap memory available, the application becomes slow and may output
			"OutOfMemoryException"s. You can increase the heap memory size at startup by using:
		</para>
		<programlisting>java -Xmx2G -jar logtracker.jar</programlisting>
		<para>or</para>
		<programlisting>java -Xmx2G -jar logtracker.exe<footnote><para><code>logtracker.exe</code> uses a default size of 1 GB as the java max heap.</para>
		</footnote></programlisting>
		<para>The java documentation explains all available memory options.</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
